# ROSE(Deepa) FRANCIS

Full Stack Web Developer equipped to deliver clean codes in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Web APIs, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, React, ORM, PWA, MongoDB, SQL, and NoSQL with efficient problem-solving ability and testified documentation skills. Proven analytical and communication skills through Business Analysis experience and bringing a keen eye for details, strong ability to implement mock-ups, and understanding of great user experience design. Educated with a master's degree in Business Administration, bachelor's degree in Engineering and Certificate in Full Stack Web Development.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JSX, SQL, NoSQL, Web API, jQuery, Bootstrap, Moment.js, Redux, PWA

#### **PROJECTS**

**Woof |** MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Mapbox, GraphQL, Stripe, JWT Url: https://woof-2021.herokuapp.com | GitHub: https://github.com/woof-board/woof

Web app for dog walking services with real time location tracking

**Shop Shop |** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Redux, GraphQL Url: https://aqueous-eyrie-25049.herokuapp.com
GitHub: https://github.com/rosefrancis-tech/shop-shop

• Ecommerce website

**EZ Budget** | JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, Google charts, Bootstrap Url: https://ez-budget10.herokuapp.com | GitHub: https://github.com/ez-budget/e-z-budget

A budgeting application to keep track of spending and savings

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Administrator, UMC High School, Toronto, Canada

2017-2020

- Pioneered the creation of monthly Newsletter in Microsoft Publish which attracted more clients.
- Diligently managed School Information System (ONSIS) and Attendance reporting system (Maplewood).
- Successfully assessed the on-going IT needs, negotiated and implemented the solutions.
- Rationally handled student and client queries and documentation needs.

Business Analyst, SynergyTech, Toronto, Canada

2016-2017

- Effectively established and followed processes to implement changes throughout the project life cycle.
- Performed Gap Analysis of existing system, created requirements documentation and presented the findings.

• Improved codes through design, development and implementation of test plans, test cases and test processes.

# Business Analyst, Blakes, Toronto, Canada

2015-2016

- Independently executed elicitation and hosted meetings with project managers and other stakeholders.
- Recognized for excellent documentation skills.
- Accurately generated deliverables such as functional and non-functional requirements, use cases, activity and sequence diagrams and user stories in Business Requirements Document, Traceability matrix and UI wireframes and user experience documents.

## **EDUCATION**

Certificate of Full Stack Web Development, University of Toronto
Certificate of Fundamentals of Business Analysis, Techno Canada Centre of Excellence, Canada Master of Business Administration, University of Kerala
WES Evaluated
Bachelor of Technology in Engineering, University of Calicut
WES Evaluated